<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Security Enthusiast &amp; Developer</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dumping tables using sqlmap;--</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will try to show a small portion of power that sqlmap possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;sequel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a web challenge from BSides SF CTF 2019. The home page shows a login form. After logging using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;guest&lt;/code&gt; account, I am presented with a list of movies with their ratings and a private note for each. The private note corresponding to Hackers movie has some reference to admin, so I guess I need to log in as admin. SQLi on the login form doesn’t work. But there is a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1337_AUTH&lt;/code&gt; cookie which on base64 decoding gives &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{&quot;username&quot;:&quot;guest&quot;,&quot;password&quot;:&quot;guest&quot;}&lt;/code&gt;. Cool, lets try SQLi here and making &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;guest&quot; and &quot;1&quot;=&quot;1&lt;/code&gt; results in successful login while &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;guest&quot; and &quot;1&quot;=&quot;2&lt;/code&gt; shows &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Invalid user&lt;/code&gt;, so it’s a blind injection. Doing some recon using my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rnehra01/web-cheats/blob/master/sqli.md#for-sqlite&quot;&gt;web-cheats&lt;/a&gt;, I am able to recognise that the backend database is SQLite as the sqlite specific payload &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;guest&quot; and EXISTS(select sqlite_version) and &quot;1&quot;=&quot;1&lt;/code&gt; works. So the task is to pull entries related to admin from the database. I have previously written a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/InfoSecIITR/write-ups/blob/master/2016/SharifCTF-2016/web-200/web-200.py&quot;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; to extract data but I have heard a lot about &lt;a href=&quot;http://sqlmap.org/&quot;&gt;sqlmap&lt;/a&gt; but haven’t used it yet. So lets give it a go and also writing that script took me a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /Dumping-tables-using-sqlmap</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Dumping-tables-using-sqlmap</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Brainwaves Cyber Security Hackathon</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the fifth edition of Brainwaves hackathon. The challenges are based on filesystems i.e. how data is stored in the hard disk. We are provided with 2 dumps of a hard disk.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /brainwaves-cyber-hack-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/brainwaves-cyber-hack-19</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>$PATH to GSoC'17</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It started almost a year back when I heard about GSoC for the first time in an introductory lecture by SDSLabs. I was quite
a noob except knowing a little about competitive coding. Then came the day when Google announced the mentoring organisations and I remember going through every single organistion but I couldn’t understand WHAT and WHERE to do. I tried sorting organisations according to programming language but nope, nothing :( I don’t even know about a commit.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /path-to-gsoc17</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/path-to-gsoc17</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
