<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/author/rnehra01/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-02-02T17:49:33+00:00</updated>
  <id>/author/rnehra01/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Ravinder Nehra | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Security Enthusiast - Developer</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">$PATH to GSoC’17</title>
      <link href="/path-to-gsoc17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="$PATH to GSoC'17" />
      <published>2017-06-14T12:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-06-14T12:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/path-to-gsoc17</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/path-to-gsoc17">&lt;p&gt;It started almost a year back when I heard about GSoC for the first time in an introductory lecture by SDSLabs. I was quite
a noob except knowing a little about competitive coding. Then came the day when Google announced the mentoring organisations and I remember going through every single organistion but I couldn’t understand WHAT and WHERE to do. I tried sorting organisations according to programming language but nope, nothing :( I don’t even know about a commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I had realised one thing that it’s not about language but it’s about field, I should have a background in any of these fields. I’ve tried Web and Android Development but neither fascinates me much. The deadline is one week away and then I met one of my classmate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://paraschetal.in&quot;&gt;Paras&lt;/a&gt; who was trying for GSoC and honestly I still didn’t have a clue. After the end of semester exams, I took him to my room and asked &lt;i&gt;What the heck is all this?&lt;/i&gt; He told me about his project and introduced me to Information Security. Well, Infosec is cool after all who doesn’t want to be a hacker, right? I spent my summer learning more about infosec, git and basic web backend to step into web exploitation. I made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rnehra01/Tic-Tac-Toe&quot;&gt;Tic-Tack-Toe&lt;/a&gt; game using javascript and put it on my GitHub. The next semester was all about Infosec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I started searching for open-source organisation to contribute in 2016 GSoC orgnisation list. Due to my interest in web security, I found &lt;a href=&quot;github.com/zaproxy&quot;&gt;OWASP ZAP&lt;/a&gt; a suitable candidate. But it’s code base is humongous. It took me almost half month till I found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zaproxy/zap-extensions/pull/706/files?diff=split#diff-0553f2ca6daf4d735deffd0ab535a2afL60&quot;&gt;TODO&lt;/a&gt;, which is doable. It is just an extension of an attack whose code is already present in the same file. With this small patch, I submitted my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zaproxy/zap-extensions/pull/706&quot;&gt;PR&lt;/a&gt;, Wooohhhuuu !!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I submitted an issue and another PR in January. Now odds are pretty good for me. Google was going to announce mentoring organisations on &lt;i&gt;27th Feb, 9:30 pm&lt;/i&gt; IST. At &lt;i&gt;9:31 pm&lt;/i&gt;, I got a message from Paras &lt;i&gt;“We’re screwed, man. OWASP isn’t selected”&lt;/i&gt;.
I knew the same thing had happened with one my senior but I still played the gamble and it didn’t work. So I had to start from sea level.&lt;br /&gt;
I finalized &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.honeynet.org/gsoc/ideas#snare-tanner&quot;&gt;Snare/Tanner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.honeynet.org/gsoc/ideas#mitmproxy-core&quot;&gt;Mitmproxy&lt;/a&gt; after searching for almost one week. The code base of Mitmproxy is large and I’m not much familiar with networks, it might take a lot of time to just understand and I wouldn’t be able to contribute much, so I put it on hold, though it’s my first choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snare/Tanner is a web security based project and also a new one, thus has a small code base. So I went for this one, contacted the mentor and started contributing by fixing bugs and writing missing tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gsoc17_before_pr.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 1.4rem&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;My Contributions before submitting final proposal&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deadline for proposal submission is 2 weeks away, so I have to worry about proposal. I took some ideas from the &lt;i&gt;Ideas page&lt;/i&gt; and a few my own to make a good list of tasks. Then I looked at my seniors’ proposals, used them as template and organize tasks with timeline. I got it reviewed from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jay_f0xtr0t&quot;&gt;Jay Bosamiya&lt;/a&gt; and my mentor. I submitted the &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/HoneynetGSoCproposal.pdf&quot;&gt;final version&lt;/a&gt; 2 days before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of accepted student projects for Google Summer of Code ‘17 came on &lt;i&gt;4th May, 9:30 pm&lt;/i&gt; IST. I opened the website at &lt;i&gt;9:30 pm&lt;/i&gt; precisely and this made my day, technically night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gsoc17_snare_tanner.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to enjoy my summer with Honeynet. I’ll keep writing regular reports on this blog itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank my mentor &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/afeena&quot;&gt;Evgeniya&lt;/a&gt; for helping me throughout the entire process, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jay_f0xtr0t&quot;&gt;Jay bosamiya&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing my proposal and folks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/InfoSecIITR&quot;&gt;InfoSecIITR&lt;/a&gt; for the entire Infosec journey, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://paraschetal.in&quot;&gt;Paras&lt;/a&gt; for getting me started.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ravinder Nehra</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="gsoc" />
      
        <category term="dev" />
      
        <category term="security" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">It started almost a year back when I heard about GSoC for the first time in an introductory lecture by SDSLabs. I was quite a noob except knowing a little about competitive coding. Then came the day when Google announced the mentoring organisations and I remember going through every single organistion but I couldn’t understand WHAT and WHERE to do. I tried sorting organisations according to programming language but nope, nothing :( I don’t even know about a commit.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
